[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 32]
[제32화]
Come check Lifei out.
잠시 려비를 살펴보시오
Her meridians are reconnected.
경맥은 다시 이어졌소
Lifei.
려비
Why did you give me your cultivation?
어째서 다들 수위를 저한테 주신 겁니까?
We're already advanced in years.
우리도 다 늙었으니
The spirit energy
영기를 남겨봤자
is useless to us now.
쓸모없다
Elder Zhu.
주옹
Don't dwell on that.
더는 얘기하지 마라
Lifei,
려비야
just go.
빨리 가보아라
Go?
간다니
Where to?
어디로 가란 말씀입니까?
Has the mountain-sea barrier been broken?
산해결계가 깨진 겁니까?
We can't escape this great calamity.
결국 이 겁을 피할 수 없구나
The Sea Calamity came from the bloodshed of immortal sects.
해운은 본래 선문의 살육에서 비롯된 것이다
This sin is of our own making,
우리가 지은 업보니
and we must bear it ourselves.
마땅히 우리가 짊어져야 한다
Leave this to us.
너는 신경 쓰지 마라
Elder Zhu,
주옹
do you also know the legend of the Sea Calamity?
선생님도 해운의 전설을 아십니까?
Years ago, to hunt for the Divine Tree,
옛날 내가 건목을 찾으려고
I pored over ancient scrolls in the Central Plains.
중토 고적을 모두 찾아다녔었다
One scroll recorded
그리고 한 고찰에 적혀 있었는데
that 1,000 years ago,
천 년 전에
a woman who could absorb heaven and earth's spirit energy
한 천지영기를 흡수할 수 있는 여인이
was slain by immortals in the East Sea.
동해에서 선문에게 살해당했다지
That marked the first arrival of the Sea Calamity.
그 뒤로 첫 해운이 내렸다
The Sea Calamity is divine retribution.
해운은 천벌이다
We cannot abide anything
우리가 우리와
different from us
다른 것들을 받아들이지 못해
and seek only to destroy it.
파괴하려고만 했기에
Our ignorance
우리의 무지함이
brought forth this calamity.
이 재난을 초래한 것이다
That woman was the Divine Tree.
그 여인은 건목입니까?
The Divine Tree caused the Sea Calamity
해운은 건목에 의해 내려진 것이니
and shall end it.
건목으로 끝내야 합니다
Lifei, you've been reborn as a human.
려비, 너는 다시 태어난 인간이고
You're no different from the rest of us.
우리와 다를 바 없다
The immortal sects
선문에서
have wronged you.
네게 잘못한 거다
All things bear
모든 일은
their karmic causes and fruits.
인연이 있기에 결과가 있는 법
This fate was never yours to carry.
이건 네가 짊어져야 할 게 아니다
We will never let you sacrifice yourself.
우리도 너를 죽게 내버려두지 않을 거다
Just go.
얼른 청구로
Return to Qingqiu.
돌아가라
It's Xiuyuan!
수원이네
Lei!
뇌 사제
The world teeters on collapse.
천하가 기울어지려 하니
We must lay aside old grudges
저희는 원한을 내려놓고
and stand united.
힘을 합쳐야 합니다
Whether one person, one realm, one sect, one clan,
한 사람이든, 한 땅, 한 문파, 한 족
or human, spirit, demon, or monster,
사람이든 요괴든 마든 괴물이든
all are living beings under heaven.
모두 천하의 생령입니다
We must join hands as one.
다들 힘을 합칩시다
Succeeded.
됐네
The earth fire recedes!
지화가 물러갔습니다
Lifei.
려비
Where's Lifei?
려비는?
Oh, no.
끝났다
We can't stop it.
더 이상 막을 수 없어
This time,
이번엔
you must not take it back.
죽어도 다시 거둘 수 없습니다
I've failed my father after all.
결국 아버님의 기대를 저버렸군
We have no regrets about holding out
마지막 순간까지 지켰으니
till the very end.
후회는 없다
In the end, everything was a fleeting dream.
결국 모두 허황한 꿈에 불과하구나
It's better to stay far away
멀리 피하는 게 차라리 좋다
as long as you live safely.
괜찮으니 다행이지
♪When fate calls, I rise as a worthy one♪
♪운명이 나를 들어 올려 현인이라 한다면♪
♪I'll never back down♪
♪우선은 물러서지 않으리♪
Lifei.
려비
♪I keep my former fearless resolve, never return it♪
♪옛날의 당당한 결의는 돌려드리지 않으리♪
It's Lifei.
려비 사매다
Lifei.
려비
♪Dusk till dawn, I stay awake♪
♪밤새 잠들지 못하고♪
♪Bearing heavy missions, I ride far away♪
♪중임을 짊어지고 먼 길을 채찍질하듯 나아가며♪
Lifei.
려비
♪The hidden fire in my heart forges a massive sword♪
♪마음속 어두운 불길로 천균검을 단련하리♪
♪With you, we climb bleak cliffs beneath endless gloom♪
♪너와 함께 험한 바위를 오르며 하늘은 보이지 않고♪
Lifei.
려비
♪Bow our heads and endure bitter gales♪
♪고개 숙여 거친 바람을 마시리♪
♪Ambition surges; we hold new feasts amid thorns♪
♪웅장한 뜻이 일어나 가시밭에서 다시 잔치를 열리♪
♪Let frost, snow and rain block the long stone steps♪
♪서리와 비바람이 이 기나긴 계단을 가로막을지라도♪
♪I tread fleeting mist beneath my feet♪
♪발아래의 고난을 연기처럼 밟고 나아가리♪
♪At last I see, life's end lies boundless wild free♪
♪마침내 깨닫네, 인생의 끝은 광야임을♪
♪Don't idle away time. We shall meet atop the peak♪
♪헛되이 세월을 보내지 말자, 우리는 반드시 정상에서 만나리♪
It's enough.
이제 충분해
I'll take you away.
내가 너를 데리고 갈게
This is what I have to do.
이건 내가 반드시 해야 할 일이야
I saw the karmic cycle overseas
해외 인과를 깨달았노라
that the death of the Divine Tree causes the Sea Calamity.
건목이 사라지면 해운이 일어나고
The Sea Calamity destroys the world with spirit energy,
해운은 영기로 세상을 멸하고
while the Divine Tree is born to absorb spirit energy.
건목은 태생적으로 영기를 흡수하니
The two are intertwined
양자는 서로 연관이 있든
yet opposed.
연관이 없든
I only wish to spend my life
오직 한 평생을 바쳐
shielding Xiaobangchui from this disaster.
소봉추를 위해 이 겁을 막겠노라
The Sea Calamity began because of me,
해운은 나 때문에 일어난 거니
so only I can end it.
내가 끝내야 해
Very well.
그래
I'm with you.
내가 곁에 있어 줄게
Xiuyuan.
수원
We made a vow
우리 약속했었잖아
to live together
함께 살거나
or perish side by side.
함께 죽기로
Lifei!
려비
Master,
사부님
Xiaobangchui and Little Yecha, whom you protected,
사부님께서 지켜주신 소봉추와 야차는
can finally guard those
드디어 사부님 대신 사부님께서
on the Central Plains you cherished.
지키고 싶어 하셨던 중토 창생을 지켜냈습니다
Lifei!
려비
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival♪
♪수많은 겁난도♪
♪The lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge, past the pagoda♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나♪
♪In fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
Lifei.
려비
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
No.
안 돼
♪No calamity can rival♪
♪수많은 겁난도♪
Lifei.
려비
♪The lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge, past the pagoda♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나♪
♪In fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge, past the pagoda♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나♪
♪In fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds, break through the waves♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고 거친 파도를 깨부수니♪
♪The heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
Lifei.
려비
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과♪
Lifei.
려비
♪And falling petals♪
♪지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪
The immortal sects are far from perfect,
선문은 완벽하지 않다
yet the world holds countless warm moments,
하지만 이 세상엔 따뜻한 것들이 많다
like clusters of tiny flames,
마치 작은 불꽃들처럼
chasing away loneliness and cold, bringing hope.
적막한 한기를 몰아내고 희망을 가져다주지
Someday,
언젠가는
this world will become what Master hoped for.
그도 사부님께서 바라셨던 모습으로 변할 거다
I firmly believe
나도 그날이
that the day will come.
올 거라 믿는다
This is the aspiration of my cultivation.
이게 나의 수련심이다
My journey in the mortal world
소봉추의 이 세상 여행은
has no regrets or sorrows.
후회도 아쉬움도 없다
Generations of brilliant souls
대대로 재능이 뛰어난 이들이
roamed everywhere
해운을 평정하기 위해
to quell the Sea Calamity.
천하를 돌아다녔네
Now the calamity is finally ended,
이제 해운이 드디어 평정되었는데
but none
그들은
of them remain.
세상을 떠나게 되었구나
Still, I trust the future
하지만 미래가 그들이
will unfold just as they wished.
바라던 대로 될 거라 나는 믿소
Sir,
선생님
a letter from Mr. Mo.
묵 선생님의 편지가 왔습니다
He said the Sea Calamity has vanished,
해운이 이미 사라졌고
and Xiuyuan has sent demons back to their overseas homelands.
마족들도 뇌수원이 해외 고향으로 돌려보냈답니다
Besides,
그리고
the seaway from the Central Plains to overseas lands
중토에서 해외로 통하는 통로가
rises again after being lost for thousands of years.
수천 년 뒤로 다시 나타났답니다
Perhaps the exchange between the Central Plains
앞으로 중토와 해외는
and the outer realms can be restored.
다시 왕래할 기회가 생길 것 같습니다
Truly, only he and she could bring
역시 그 둘답군
great changes and vitality to the Central Plains.
중토에 큰 변수와 생기를 가져다주었네
Sir,
선생님
the remnant spirits of Lifei and Xiuyuan
려비와 수원의 잔령은
were taken away by the Nine-Tailed Fox and Mr. Yan.
구미호와 연 방주께서 가져가셨다는데
Is there a chance
아직
that they're still alive?
살아있는 거 아닐까요?
Heaven pities all living beings.
하늘이 모든 생령을 연민하니
Kind hearts and good deeds shall reap good karma.
착한 마음과 선한 일을 하면 복이 올 거다
There may be
그들에게도
a glimmer of hope for them.
생기가 남아 있겠지
A decade reshaped
십 년 사이
all immortal sects in the Central Plains.
중토 선문의 구도가 크게 바뀌었다
Immortal Lord, we welcome you back from seclusion!
선존님의 출관을 맞이합니다
One day,
어느 날
a purple star crashed over the Xingzheng Hall.
성정관 상공에 갑자기
It was as large as a bushel
아주 큰 자색 별이 떨어져
and foretold the arrival of an immortal.
이는 선인이 세상에 나타날 징조라 한다
Ji Tongzhou styled himself Immortal Lord Xuanhua,
기동주는 스스로 현화 선존이라 칭하고
turning the Xingzheng Hall into the state guardian sect.
성정관을 호국 선문으로 봉했다
He fought beside the Yue Emperor
월왕을 따라 남북으로 정벌하고
[Adult Ji Jingwu] and vanquished every state,
[성년 기동주] 여러 나라를 평정하여
uniting the whole realm.
천하가 모두 복종하게 했다
The Wuyue Court under Deng Xiguang
등계광은 무월정을 맡은 뒤
withdrew from the mortal realm,
속세 일에 관여하지 않고 은거 수련에 빠져
allowing the Xingzheng Hall to dominate.
성정관이 홀로 세를 떨쳤다
Ji Tongzhou sought to unify the immortal sects.
기동주는 선문을 통일하고
He sent the Xuanhua Decree to the Mountain and Sea Sects.
산해 양파에 현화령을 보내
[Wanxian Sect] Obey, or face destruction.
[만선문] 순하는 자는 흥하고
Ji Tongzhou goes too far,
기동주가 정말 너무하는군
ordering our sect to yield to the Xingzheng Hall.
만선문이 성정관에 귀속하라 요구하다니
Over the past year,
지난 일 년 사이
many sects refused to answer
여러 선문들이
the summons of the Xuanhua Decree,
현화령을 따르지 않아
only to be attacked and wiped out
성정관에게 토벌을 당해
by the Xingzheng Hall.
멸문당했답니다
I heard
듣기로
the Dizang Sect has been destroyed as well.
지장문도 멸문했답니다
Jiao,
사저
I'm heading to the Xingzheng Hall
제가 성정관에 가서
to return the Xuanhua Decree.
현화령을 돌려주겠습니다
No,
안 된다
it's far too dangerous.
너무 위험하다
Ji Tongzhou was once our fellow disciple.
기동주는 그래도 저와 옛 벗이었으니
He won't harm me
옛정을 생각해서라도
for old friendship's sake.
저에게 함부로 대하진 않을 겁니다
Besides,
게다가
we've had no word
해운이 지난 뒤
from Changyue and Ye since the Sea Calamity.
언니와 오라버니의 소식이 없어져
I want to ask him about them.
그를 찾아 여쭙고 싶었습니다
Fine.
그래
Stay alert.
만사 조심해야 한다
Don't push yourself
만약 무슨 일이 생기면
if anything goes wrong.
억지로 버티지 마라
Your Highness's painting skills grow finer by the day.
왕야의 화공이 날로 늘어나시네요
What's wrong? Unwell?
어디 불편하냐?
Nothing. I think I ate something bad.
아닙니다, 아마 음식을 잘못 먹은 것 같습니다
Get rid of it.
지워라
Your Highness,
왕야
this is our child.
저희 아이입니다
I beg you.
제발
Spare the child, please.
아이는 살려주십시오
This must not happen again.
이런 일은 다시 있어서는 안 됐어야 했다
Do not cling to foolish hopes.
더는 희망을 품지 마라
Your Highness,
왕야
I can give up everything.
묘청은 모든 걸 다 버려도 되지만
I'm begging you.
제발
Spare our child, please.
우리의 아이만은 살려주십시오
Are you dead or alive?
대체 죽은 거야 살아있는 거야?
Young lady.
낭자
Miaoqing.
묘청
He's utterly insane.
정말 미쳤네요
He sees you as Lifei's substitute
묘쳥을 려비 대역으로 삼고서는
and won't even spare his own child.
자기 자식마저 버리려 하다니
Let's confront him right now.
지금 같이 만나러 가시죠
No.
안 됩니다
Gelin,
가림
let go first.
먼저 손 놔
I know you mean well.
저는 낭자의 호의를 알고 있습니다
Don't worry about me.
너무 걱정하지 마십시오
I only want to give birth to this child.
저는 아이를 무사히 낳고 싶을 뿐
Nothing else
나머지는
matters.
중요하지 않습니다
[Xuanhua Palace]
[현화궁]
Gelin, Lu Li,
가림, 육리 형님
His Highness expected your arrival,
왕야께서 오실 줄 미리 짐작하셨더니
and here you are.
정말 찾아오셨네요
His Highness has stepped out,
왕야께서 외출하셨습니다
but he will return shortly.
곧 돌아오십니다
Please wait for him in his chamber.
먼저 왕야 방에서 잠시 기다리십시오
I don't know why
왜인지
this chamber reminds me of the academy.
이 방이 서원 생각나게 하네요
Looks just like our disciple lodgings, right?
제자 방과 많이 닮지 않았느냐?
Tongzhou holds onto old memories.
동주는 역시 옛정을 잊지 않았네요
What's wrong?
왜 그러냐?
I can't explain it.
저도 모르겠어요
No.
아니야
It can't be true.
아닐 거야
Gelin, calm down.
가림, 일단 진정해
It's only a blade shoulder.
그저 검 받침대일 뿐이야
The sword is the imperial token of Gaolu.
이 검은 고로 황족의 신물입니다
Ye would never part with it.
오라버니는 죽어도 몸에서 떼지 않아요
So it's the imperial token of Gaolu.
고로 황족의 물건이었군
No wonder even karmic fire could not burn it.
그래서 업화로도 태우기 어려웠었구나
- You killed them. - Gelin.
- 왕야가 그들을 죽였습니까? - 가림
Why?
왜
Tell me, why?
왜 그랬습니까?
They tried to stop me from killing Lei Xiuyuan.
그들이 내가 뇌수원을 죽이는 걸 막으려 했다
They brought it on themselves.
그러니 이건 그들이 자초한 거다
Gelin,
가림
they died a decade ago.
그들은 십 년 전에 이미 죽었다
I treated all of you as friends,
난 너희를 벗으로 여겼거늘
yet every one of you
너희는 하나같이
took that Demon Lord's side
그 마군 편만 들고
and betrayed me one after another.
하나같이 나를 배신했다
All of you
너희들은
deserve to die!
모두 죽어야 한다
Ji Tongzhou, you beast!
기동주, 이런 짐승 같은 놈
I'll kill you!
죽여버릴 거야
Take one more step forward,
한 걸음만 더 다가오면
and she'll be consumed by karmic fire instantly.
그 애는 바로 업화에 타버릴 것이다
Ji Tongzhou,
기동주
you let us find Ye Ye's blade shoulder
일부러 엽엽의 검 받침대를 발견하게 하고
and then grievously wounded Gelin.
가림까지 죽이려 하다니
What exactly are you after?
대체 뭘 하려는 것이냐?
You're the Jiufeng Clan's leader, huh?
네가 구봉족 족장이라 그랬지
I've heard you spirits have far-reaching intelligence
듣기로 너희 요족의 귀가 밝다고 하던데
and know every landform of the islands
해외 천주만도의 지형도
like the back of your hand.
아주 익숙하다지
In six months,
반년 줄 테니
bring Jiang Lifei before me.
강려비를 내 앞으로 데려와라
If you fail,
아니면
prepare to collect Gelin's ashes.
가림의 유골을 거둘 준비나 해라
Don't hurt her!
해치지 마!
I agree to your terms.
약속할게
Mark my words,
기억하라
only six months.
딱 반년이다
A decade ago,
십 년 전
the Divine Tree and Yecha sacrificed themselves
건목과 야차가 목숨을 내던져
to fend off the Sea Calamity.
함께 해운을 막고
They ended the age-old karmic hatred,
전생의 오랜 원한을 풀었으며
breaking the curse to be reborn.
저주를 깨고 다시 태어났다
The Divine Tree's spirit meridians were completely shattered,
건목은 영맥이 모두 끊어지고
and Yecha lost his supreme power.
야차는 무상법력을 잃었으며
Though their cultivation faded drastically,
두 사람의 수위가 크게 줄었으나
they finally gained what they longed for.
오히려 바라던 대로 살게 되었지
Lifei and the others have all left.
려비는 이미 떠났는데
Why are you still writing this tale?
왜 아직도 여기서 이야기를 쓰고 있나?
The story should have ended.
본래 끝났는데
Yet now, back in the Central Plains,
중토로 돌아오니
we await a new ending.
또 결말을 기다려야 하는 상황이네
Years ago,
그 해
when Qingcheng roamed overseas with me,
나와 청성이 해외를 돌아다녔을 때
he was worried about the Central Plains
그는 중토를 걱정해서
and insisted on returning.
꼭 돌아가야 한다고 했지
This time,
이번엔
there must be a different conclusion.
꼭 다른 결말이 찾아왔으면 좋겠네
But old karmic ties in the world remain.
그러나 이 세상의 옛 인연은 끊어지지 않았으니
Ji Tongzhou holds Baili Gelin hostage,
기동주는 백리가림을 미끼로 삼아
forcing Lu Li of the Jiufeng Clan to bring back the Divine Tree.
구봉족 육리더러 건목을 잡아 오라고 한다
Reluctant to leave her old friend,
건목은 옛 벗들을 버릴 수 없어
the Divine Tree travels home with Yecha.
야차와 함께 길을 나선다
Lifei, don't grieve.
려비, 슬퍼하지 마
Once you make a choice,
선택을 했으면
you must bear its consequences.
결과를 감당해야 해
Xiuyuan.
수원
Lifei,
려비
my choice
나의 선택은
has always been you.
줄곧 너였다
Stand up.
자
Thank you.
고마워요
Lifei.
려비 낭자
You're with child.
회임했으면
Don't do heavy labor.
앞으로 힘든 일은 하지 말고
Focus on safely giving birth to the baby.
무사히 아이를 낳으십시오
Lifei,
려비 낭자
do not blame His Highness.
왕야를 탓하지 마십시오
He...
그가...
He killed my dearest friends
그자는 제 가장 친한 벗을 죽였고
and took Gelin captive.
가림마저 붙잡아갔습니다
His Highness
왕야...
had no other choice.
왕야는 어쩔 수 없는 상황이었을 겁니다
He never meant to hurt anyone.
일부러 그런 게 아닐 겁니다
Does that excuse how he treated you?
그럼 그대를 이렇게 대하는 것도 어쩔 수 없는 건가요?
He's cold to me
그가 저한테 이러는 건
only because
제가 결코
I can never be you.
려비 낭자가 아니기 때문입니다
You'll never be me.
그대는 당연히 제가 아니지요
You belong to yourself.
묘청은 묘청일 뿐
You've sacrificed so much for him.
그를 위해 이렇게 많은 일을 했는데
He ought to cherish and treat you well,
잘 아껴주고 잘 대해줘야지
instead of...
이렇게...
I don't blame him.
왕야 탓 아닙니다
I chose this willingly.
제가 원해서 한 일이에요
I have no spirit energy
제 몸에는 영기가 다 사라져
to heal your wounds.
치료해 줄 수 없어요
Keep this money and protective talismans
여기 은화와 호신부가 있으니
to safeguard yourself.
가지고 다니며 몸을 보살피세요
Lifei,
려비 낭자
you're going to see His Highness, right?
왕야 찾으러 가시려는 겁니까?
Take good care of yourself
본인과 아이를 위해
and your child.
몸 잘 챙기세요
What are your odds?
성공할 확률이 얼마나 되오?
I'm Miaoqing. Greetings, Your Highness.
묘청, 왕야를 뵙습니다
Ji Tongzhou is using Gelin as bait,
기동주가 가림을 미끼로 삼은 건
all to lure you here.
낭자를 노리는 거요
If you go over there
이렇게 다가가면
and he sees through your disguise...
정체가 들통날 뿐이오
It won't happen.
안 그럴 거예요
I've never failed at tricking anyone.
저 소봉추는 사람을 속일 때 들통난 적이 없어요
No way.
안 돼
Ji Tongzhou is far too shrewd to be fooled.
기동주는 속이기 쉽지 않아
I know this is pulling chestnuts out of the fire,
지금 불구덩이로 뛰어든다는 걸 알아
yet we have no other options right now.
하지만 지금 상황에 다른 방법은 없잖아
Don't worry.
걱정 마
I'll sneak in to find out where Gelin is.
그냥 가림의 소식만 알아보고 올 거야
I'll avoid him at all costs if I can.
절대 그와 마주칠 리 없어
Nothing will go wrong.
괜찮을 거야
I'm coming with you.
내가 같이 갈게
You...
너...
You said
괜찮다고
nothing would go wrong.
말했잖아
It's settled then.
이렇게 결정했다
Miaoqing, you're back!
묘청, 돌아왔습니까?
Mr. Zhao.
조 장군
It's been ages. Where have you been?
이렇게 오랫동안 어딜 가셨습니까?
While you were gone,
없는 동안
His Highness was in a bad mood every day.
왕야께서 매일 기분이 좋지 않으셨습니다
We all hoped you'd return soon.
다들 낭자가 돌아오기만을 기다렸습니다
I just wandered around.
그저 여기저기 돌아다녔습니다
I've missed His Highness deeply, too.
저도 왕야가 그리웠습니다
I heard Miss Baili visited
듣기로 며칠 전에
His Highness the other day,
백리 낭자께서 왕야를 찾으러 오셨고
and they seemed to argue.
다툼도 일어났다던데
Did His Highness get hurt?
왕야께서 다치지 않으셨죠?
She's no match for him.
그녀가 왕야의 상대가 되겠습니까?
He locked her up long ago.
왕야께서 이미 그녀를 가뒀습니다
Where is she being locked?
어디에 가두셨습니까?
She is...
그게...
Miaoqing,
묘청
why bother yourself with this?
왜 그걸 물어보십니까?
Who's there?
누구냐?
This Truth-Revealing Talisman
진술부 한 장으로
will make us safe and sound.
우리 둘 다 다치지 않고 수월하게 처리하자고
Gelin!
가림
Miaoqing.
묘청
Stand back.
비키십시오
Lifei,
려비
you've come back.
드디어 돌아왔네요
Yes.
그래
She's finally returned.
드디어 돌아왔네
Welcome home.
집에 돌아온 걸 환영한다
Ji Tongzhou,
기동주
you beast!
짐승 같은 놈
It's been a decade.
십 년이 지나
I've waited for this moment.
드디어 너를 만나게 되었네
Let's hold our wedding ceremony anew.
우리 혼례식을 다시 올리자
This time,
이번엔
no one will ever tear you
아무도 널
away from me.
데려갈 수 없을 거야
We can stay together forever.
우린 영원히 함께할 수 있어
That can't be.
꿈도 꾸지 마
Xiuyuan and I are married.
난 이미 수원과 혼인했어
What did you say?
뭐라고?
She said we're married. Can't you understand?
나와 혼인했다는데 못 알아들었느냐?
Lifei.
려비
Lei Xiuyuan!
뇌수원
Ji Tongzhou!
기동주
Watch out!
조심해
Run!
빨리 가
Why not unleash your Yecha power?
왜 야차의 힘을 쓰지 않아?
You're the Demon Lord.
너는 마족이다
Don't think the world will accept you
네가 해운을 막았다고
just because you ended the Sea Calamity.
세상 사람들이 너를 받아줄 것 같아?
The Sea Calamity arose
해운은
precisely because of you.
너 때문에 생긴 거다
You're wrong.
해운은 야차가 아니라
It was born from your own greed.
너희들의 탐욕 때문에 생긴 거다
The Divine Tree never fell in love with your ancestor.
건목은 네 선조와 만난 적도 없었다
He coveted the Divine Tree's power,
그가 건목의 힘을 욕심내
hoping to seize it for himself.
홀로 차지하고 싶었던 거다
[Ancestor of the Ji clan] When he failed,
[기씨 선조] 그가 건목을 차지하지 못하자
he colluded with the immortal sects
선문들과 손을 잡고
to ambush her in the East Sea,
동해에서 건목을 습격해
costing her life.
그녀를 죽인 것이다
The ancient gods were furious
고신께서 그 일에 노하셔서
and unleashed the Sea Calamity to punish you all.
벌로 해운을 내리신 거다
You're lying!
헛소리 마라
Had your ancestor not absorbed
건목의 힘을 흡수하지 않았으면
the Divine Tree's power,
네 선조가
how could he have forged the Xuanhua Karmic Fire?
어찌 현화업화를 수련했겠어?
Tongzhou, you know better than anyone
동주, 업화를 수련하려면
what is required to master the karmic fire.
무엇이 필요한지 네가 가장 알고 있을 것이다
The Sea Calamity is long gone.
해운은 지나갔으니
It's time to let go of your obsession.
네 집념도 이젠 끊어야 된다
You have attained an immortal physique,
너는 이미 선신을 만들어
and we stand no match for you.
우린 네 상대가 안 된다
Why can't you let this go?
왜 아직도 내려놓지 않아?
Let go?
내려놔?
How could I ever let go?
어떻게 내려놓을 수 있겠어?
If you had not stubbornly gone your own way
너희가 멋대로 움직이고
and left me all alone,
날 버리지 않았으면
the Sea Calamity would never have happened.
해운은 다가오지 않았을 것이고
Ye Ye and Changyue would still be alive.
엽엽과 창월도 죽지 않았을 것이다
It is all your fault.
전부 너희 탓이다
Because you chose Yecha.
너희가 야차를 택한 탓이다
Ji Tongzhou,
기동주
enough of your madness.
제발 미친 짓 그만해라
All the slaughter is of your own making,
네가 지은 살육의 죄를
but you shift the blame to others.
남에게 돌리지 마
How can you face Ye Ye and the rest?
엽엽 그들한테 미안하지도 않아?
Mad?
미친 짓?
I only regret I didn't lose my mind sooner.
일찍 미치지 않은 게 후회된다
Your Highness, stop,
왕야, 그만하십시오
or you will live to regret it.
아니면 후회하실 겁니다
Even you betrayed me, too!
너도 날 배신했느냐?
Get lost!
꺼져
Xiuyuan!
수원
Uncle, save me!
숙부님, 살려주십시오
Release them,
놓아주거라
or I'll kill him.
아니면 죽여버릴 것이다
Uncle,
숙부님
Lifei once saved my life
려비 고모께서 저를 구해주셨었고
and helped the Yue State.
월국도 도와주신 적 있습니다
Spare them.
그들을 풀어주십시오
Let there be no more killing.
더 이상 사람을 죽이지 마세요
Let them leave.
그냥 보내주십시오
Silence!
닥쳐라
With such cowardice,
이렇게 나약해서
how will you guard the Yue State's realm?
어찌 월국 강산을 지켜낼 수 있겠느냐?
Xiuyuan!
수원
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난도 향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어 가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪